There's no reason to be so wary of us.
你們用不著那麼提防我們
Although I would like to say that
雖然我很想說我們是來詢問
we are here to inquire about the fire accident from yesterday,
昨天那起火災的相關事宜的
in fact, I am here for personal reasons.
不過我其實是為私事而來的
It's just lunchtime,
正好到我們的午休時間了
and I thought of doing divination.
我就想說來你們這占卜一下
Are you going to give it a try, Arase?
荒瀨 你也要來試試嗎
I'm not really interested in such things.
我對這種事不太感興趣
If I get the result, "Quit your job as a police officer because you have bad luck,"
若是得到“因為你運氣差 所以辭掉警察的工作吧”這樣的結果
wouldn't that make things difficult for me?
不是會令我很為難嗎
You are still as troublesome as ever.
你這傢伙還真是一如既往的麻煩啊
Well, then, why don't you do divination for me alone?
那麼 就替我一個人占卜一下吧
Alright.
我明白了
Please go to the room next door.
請你移步隔壁的房間吧
Okay, it's over here.
好的 是這邊喔
Please follow me.
請你們跟我走
(Dead Mount, Death Play)
《屍體如山的死亡遊戲》
But speaking of which, as a student, you have become a diviner.
話說回來 你身為一介學生卻當起了占卜師
Although there is nothing wrong with that,
雖然這沒什麼問題
your business application must be submitted within a month per regulations.
不過得麻煩你遵守規定 在一個月內遞交開業申請
That's all for routine matters.
算了 例行公事的話就說這麼多
Young man, there is something I want to ask you for help with.
少年 我要拜託你一件事
Please guide poor police officers like us.
請你為我們這些可憐的警察指條明路
I'm not going to assist you in determining where the escaped prisoner is now.
我不會替你們占卜 越獄的人如今身在何處
For that matter, it's our responsibility.
那件事是我們的責任
We will find a way to solve it.
我們會想辦法解決的
Anyway, if you can predict the future,
不說這個了 如果你能預知未來
I hope you can help us prevent murders from happening.
希望你能幫我們預防殺人案件的發生
My divination is not about predicting the future.
我的占卜並不是在預知未來
In essence, I am just observing the trends of the future.
說到底我不過是在 觀察“未來的走向”罷了
The paths you have walked in the past
你過去曾走過的道路
and the countless possible paths that extend into the future.
以及延伸至未來的無數條可能的道路
I haven't seen him show such an expression at home.
我在家裡可沒見過他 露出這樣的表情
Looks quite like the real deal.
看上去倒是挺像有那麼一回事
He must have been tempered on the underworld to some extent.
他應該或多或少 都曾在修羅場中磨練過吧
If fake Polka is plotting something behind the scenes,
如果假波爾卡在背地裡 謀劃著什麼見不得人的勾當
reporting to these two people who look like police officers
這兩個人看起來像是警察
could be a means of getting rid of him.
我向他們告發也不失為一種手段
I don't need to divine your profession.
您的職業
I can tell without divination.
我不需要占卜也能知道
It's hard not to know about that.
這種事想不知道都難吧
If I observe more carefully,
若是更為仔細地觀察
I find countless hands
我發現在您的周圍
surrounding you.
環繞著無數雙手
To protect the peace of the people,
為了守護眾人安寧的手
you have offered advice and shelter to young boys and girls.
您給予少男少女們勸誡與庇護
You sometimes become a shield to protect others from knife-wielding attackers.
時而化身為盾 擋在試圖傷人的手持刀刃者面前
-He knows that I belong to the Community Safety Division. -Sometimes, you become a heroic steel cable
-他已經知道了我隸屬於生活安全科 -時而化身為束縛刀刃的鋼索
-Perhaps Takumi Kuruya has gathered -that restrains sharp weapons in battle.
-恐怕是身在某處的繰屋匠 -英勇奮戰
-intelligence and provided it to him. -You guide people like yourself.
-在把他蒐集到的情報提供給他吧 -指引像您這樣的人
That headscarf must have
那個頭巾裡
-some kind of communication device inside. -For your own safety…
-應該裝有通訊設備之類的東西吧 -為了您自身的安寧
He must be Iwanome from the Community Safety Division.
他是生活安全科的岩野目吧
It's really annoying that troublemakers keep coming one after another.
真是的 麻煩的傢伙接連不斷地找上門
Probably because when you visited your ancestors and their houses,
那多半是因為您在尋訪您祖先 及其住所的過程當中
you saw many flower cards of ladies.
看到了很多異性的花牌
He even investigated my blind date history.
他連我相親的事都調查過了啊
Your past has
您的過往當中
left a huge scar,
殘留有一道巨大的傷痕
even causing you to lose your wings.
其甚至令您折損了羽翼
As long as this scar remains on your mind,
只要這道傷痕仍舊壓在您心頭
you can only continue to move forward on the underwater path.
您便只能繼續在水底的道路上前行
Your words have piqued my interest.
你這話讓我相當感興趣
So, will you tell me
所以 你這占卜師會告訴我
the method to get rid of this scar?
抹去傷痕的方法嗎
Do you want to get rid of this scar?
您想要抹去這道傷痕嗎
This is hard to say.
這可不好說
If there is the path that can guide me towards
只不過 若是存在能夠指引我前往
the place where the guy who caused this scar resides,
令我背負上這道傷痕的那傢伙 所在之處的“道路”的話
then please do point it out for me.
請你務必指點一二
Those shattered wings
那破碎的羽翼
will become the milestones that guide you forward.
將成為指引你前行的路標
That pen scared me a bit.
那…那根筆有點嚇到我了
Incredible.
真是不可思議
This voice sounds exactly like the one
這個聲音
I heard last night when someone was writing something.
跟我昨晚聽到的 像是在寫什麼東西的聲音一模一樣
I see.
原來如此
They were chatting about comics and games,
他們在聊漫畫跟遊戲的同時
while constantly practicing this kind of magic.
一直在練習這種魔術嗎
Mr. Iwa?
岩先生
Why?
為什麼
What do you really know,
四乃山波爾卡
Polka Shinoyama?
你究竟知道些什麼
Iwanome.
岩野目
Is this for me? This is rare.
這是請我的嗎 真是少見
The brand is one that I like.
是我喜歡的牌子
I still can't smoke this kind of cigarette.
我還是抽不來這種煙
What is this sign?
這個標誌是什麼
Do you remember it?
你記住了嗎
Hmm, I roughly remember it.
嗯 我大概記住了
Don't forget it.
不要忘了它
We must never let others see this sign.
但也絕不能讓其他人看到這個標誌
It is not only the milestone we are pursuing,
它既是我們所要追尋的路標
but also a one-way ticket to death.
亦是喚來死亡的單程票
Why did you draw this?
你為什麼畫了“這個”
I'm just pointing the way for you.
我不過是 為您指明道路而已
You only need to follow your heart
您只需遵照內心所想
and take actions.
然後採取行動便好
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉抱歉
I was a little scared.
我有點被嚇到了
Take it.
收下吧
This is the fee for divination.
這是占卜的費用
I can't take that much money.
那個 我不能收下這麼大一筆錢
Just take it.
別客氣
It includes compensation for wrinkling your clothes.
這些錢包含了弄皺你衣服的賠償
We won't bother you anymore today.
今天我們就不再繼續打擾你們了
Goodbye.
拜拜
Goodbye, Polka Shinoyama.
回頭見 四乃山波爾卡
Corpse God.
“屍神殿”
The person who has divined for you here
在這里為你占卜的人
is not Polka Shinoyama
並不是四乃山波爾卡
but the Corpse God.
而是“屍神殿”
Alright.
我知道了
The title of a diviner is very important.
畢竟身為占卜師 名號是很重要的
However, your title sounds like a calamity,
不過 你的名號
which makes me feel a little overwhelmed.
聽起來像是災厄 這讓我有點不知所措
What's calamity?
災厄是什麼
Do you know those two people just now?
你認識剛才那兩個人嗎
They are police officers.
他們是警察喔
They seemed to come here because of the fire accident.
他們看起來像是因為那起火災才來的
The attitude of that police officer was strange just now.
那名警察剛才的態度很奇怪
What exactly was written on that paper?
那張紙上究竟寫了什麼
Maybe it's a secret related to the fake Polka.
或許是跟假波爾卡有關的秘密
I need to find out.
我有必要一探究竟
Young lady.
大小姐
I'm going to buy ingredients for dinner.
我去買晚餐的食材
Thank you.
是嗎 謝謝你
Then I'll leave it to you.
那就拜託你了
If you have time, please also pick up some shark-related merchandise
有空的話 你就順便再買些鯊魚週邊回來
on the way back, even if I have had a few of them.
買到重複的也沒關係
Yes.
好…好的
CURRY SHOP NANCY One bite is enough to taste the deliciousness
(咖哩店 南希) 圓滾滾的大塊肉
of the round, large chunks of meat
鮮嫩的蝦
and the fresh, tender shrimp
只需一口便可感受到其美味
before the spicy surge that will follow.
隨後一股辛辣便會翻湧上來
It's really delicious.
真是太好吃了
Mr. Iwa, why do you always have such an expression when you eat here?
岩先生 你在這裡吃飯的時候 總是會露出那種表情呢
That's so exaggerated.
那種誇張的表情
If you have anything else to say to me, just go ahead.
你要是有什麼想對我說的 那你就說吧
You're making me feel awkward.
你這樣子 搞得氣氛好尷尬
Can I ask you about that thing?
啊 我可以問你那件事嗎
Although I don't really want anyone to bring up that matter,
雖說我不是很希望有人問起那件事
it's still better than eating in silence.
但這樣總比我們悶著頭吃飯要好
Then I will ask.
那我就不客氣地問了
What exactly happened just now?
剛才究竟是怎麼回事
Oh, sorry.
啊 抱歉
I lost my composure.
我剛才失了分寸
That doesn't seem like you.
這不像是岩先生你的風格
Isn't threatening others my responsibility?
威脅他人 不應該是我的職責嗎
If I am the whip,
如果我是鞭子
then you are maltose mixed with poison.
那麼岩先生你就是混有毒藥的麥芽糖
Am I right?
沒錯吧
That's what I said before.
這不是我以前說過的話嗎
I'm speechless to respond.
真是令我無話可說
What exactly was written on that paper?
那張紙上究竟寫了什麼
Sorry.
抱歉
Let me think it over on the way.
讓我在路上再理一理
I'll tell you when we get to the next destination.
等到了“接下來要去的地方” 我就告訴你
Understood, then I'll just wait a little longer.
明白了 那我就再等一下好了
I felt relieved when I saw you return to your usual state.
看到岩先生恢復了平常的樣子 我也就放下心來了
Well, now I can't help but calm down.
嗯 這下不想冷靜下來都不行了
My impulsivity caused the whole mess before.
之前就是因為我太過衝動 所以才把整件事搞砸了
I have an idea.
有了有了
I'll just follow them for a while.
我再稍微跟蹤他們一段時間吧
I bought the ingredients and shark-related merchandise at the grocery stores.
食材和鯊魚週邊都在店裡買到了
I've really done a good job.
我在工作上真是滴水不漏
I heard Shinoyama's house burned down. I was quite happy at first,
聽說四乃山家起火了 我原本還挺高興的
but I didn't expect this building to be affected too.
沒想到連這棟大樓都受到了牽連
Leader, isn't this vault fireproof?
組長 這座金庫不是防火的嗎
There's something I must take out.
有件東西我必須要取出來
What if the police or firefighters see it…
要是被警察或者消防的人看到…
Is it something bad?
是什麼不好的東西嗎？
Stop talking
別廢話了
and keep watch.
給我閉嘴 好好把風…
Tick-tock, tick-tock.
嘀噠噠嘀噠噠
Blow the little trumpet.
吹起小喇叭
The toy march goes tick-tock.
玩具的進行曲 嘀噠噠
THIS WORLD IS A BUGGY PROGRAM A line of puppet soldiers,
(This world is a buggy program) 一行人偶的軍隊啊
little horses and dogs together, tick-tock.
小馬小狗也在一起 嘀噠噠
Summer bugs,
夏天的蟲子
go wherever you want.
就隨你去吧
Of course, it goes wherever it wants.
那當然得隨牠去了
Turn, turn.
我轉我轉
It's not parchment,
這不是羊皮紙啊
nor pigskin.
也不是豬皮
Could it be human skin?
這該不會是人皮吧
This is the bug you mentioned, right?
這就是你說的“缺陷”吧
The Firestarter.
赴火之蟲
I've decided on the theme for my comeback performance.
我決定好復活公演的題材了
Let's make the world more lively together.
大家一起讓世界變得熱鬧起來吧
Oh, what a disaster it is.
唉 真是災難一場啊
By the way, why did that detective
話說回來 那名刑警
suddenly grab your collar?
為什麼突然揪住了你的衣領
What did you ask the soul attached to that guy?
你到底問了附身在那傢伙 身上的靈魂什麼事情啊
That person wasn't possessed by anything.
那個人沒有被任何東西附身
Really?
咦 真的嗎
Actually, not many people
其實沒有多少人
will be possessed.
會被靈魂給附身
At the time, I was providing advice
那時候
for him based on what Takumi
我就只好根據匠調查到的事情
had researched.
為對方提供了建議
Huh?
什麼嘛
It means that you wrote something casually and it angered that guy?
意思是說 你隨便寫了些東西 就惹怒了那傢伙嗎
No, I think it's because…
不 我想那是因為…
Hey, why did you keep it from me?
喂 妳為什麼要瞞著我
Oh, what could I possibly hide from you?
哎呀 我能有什麼事瞞著你呢
To be honest, I have given up.
老實說我已經放棄了
Right.
是啊
I cannot help but believe in this kind of thing.
我沒法不相信這種事
That person cannot die easily.
那個人不可能輕易死掉
What are you talking about?
你在說什麼呢
At this point, don't play dumb anymore.
事到如今妳就別裝糊塗了
That person disappeared from this city five years ago.
那個人在這座城市消失了五年
Only you can do such a thing.
能做到這種事的就只有你們了吧
And I know Polka Shinoyama is related to you.
而且 我也知道 妳跟四乃山波爾卡有關係
Who is that person?
那個人是誰
He unexpectedly conveyed a message to me through divination.
沒想到他居然能 通過“占卜”向我傳達消息
What Polka Shinoyama wrote down
四乃山波爾卡寫的東西
should be information that only I and that person knew.
是應該只有“我”和“那個人” 知道的內容
If he mentioned it to anyone other than me,
如果他跟除了我以外的某個人 提起過這件事
it would be you.
那麼 那個人恐怕只可能會是妳
Very sorry.
十分抱歉
I have no idea what you're talking about.
我不知道你在說什麼
Who exactly is the person you're referring to?
你口中的那個人究竟是誰
Don't play dumb anymore.
妳不要再裝傻了
He said he hoped to handle it on his own,
因為他說希望交給他來處理
so I handed it over to him.
所以我就交給他來辦了
So I don't know what he wrote on the paper.
所以我不知道他到底在紙上寫了什麼
The room was dark, and I couldn't see clearly either.
房間裡光線很暗 我也看不太清
What?
什麼
Are you saying that the person who wrote something to the detective is…
喂 你是說對那名刑警 寫下什麼東西的人是…
He is a prosecutor who is quite unpopular with the police
他是因為跟我一起胡鬧
because he used to fool around with me,
而在警察那邊相當不受待見的檢察官
and he is also your important senior.
並且也是妳重要的前輩
-Mr. Hosorogi.
-細呂木先生啊
So, Mr. Hosorogi.
這麼說 細呂木先生
Do you know that detective?
你認識那名刑警囉
SHINJUKU IS REALLY SMALL OR SHOULD I SAY "THE WATER RUNS DEEP"
(新宿還真是小啊) (或者是說“水還真深”)
This is quite a memorable name.
真是個相當令人懷念的名字呢
Well, I may not have said this name for a long time.
嗯 我也許久不曾 將這個名字說出口了
Your looks happy,
你的表情看起來有些開心
but you are also angry.
卻也帶著些許怒意
That's natural.
那當然
After all, only I was being played around.
畢竟只有我一個人被耍的團團轉
As for the reason why I'm angry,
至於我生氣的理由
it's mainly related to what happened with Polka Shinoyama.
主要還是 跟四乃山波爾卡的那件事有關
What happened to that child?
那孩子怎麼了
The purpose of the Community Safety Division
生活安全科的存在意義
is not to provide guidance to children,
並非是對孩子們進行輔導
but to protect
而是守護他們的
their past, present, and future.
過去 現在以及未來
This is what Mr. Hosorogi told me
這是當年還在擔任 所轄地區局長的
when I served as the director of the region.
細呂木先生曾對我說過的話
Oh, that's really strange.
哎呀 那還真是奇怪
Are you saying Mr. Hosorogi
你是說細呂木先生
involved Polka in something?
把波爾卡這樣的孩子 捲進了什麼事當中嗎
I'm not sure if you're doing it
我不清楚妳是因為形勢所迫
out of necessity or intentionally.
還是有意為之
If it's the former,
若是前者
then I should confront you face-to-face.
那我就更該當面指責妳了
There's no need to involve
妳沒必要將小孩子捲進
the child in this mess.
這一團糟的渾水當中吧
At least,
至少
I don't remember ever involving him in anything.
我不記得自己曾做過 將小孩子捲進來那種事
I just lent the building to
我不過是出於好意
Polka Shinoyama out of goodwill.
才將那棟大樓借給四乃山波爾卡的
I was able to connect with a key member of Shinoyama Group.
既然這麼做就能夠 和四乃山集團的重要人物搭上關係
How could I let such a tempting opportunity slip by?
我怎麼可能放過如此誘人的機會呢
I see.
這樣啊
If your good intentions stem from self-interest, they're still valid.
如果妳的好意是以利益為目的 那的確也算是十分充足的動機了
In that case,
既然如此
you should not incite them to get involved in Mr. Hosorogi's affairs.
妳更不應該讓他們牽涉進 細呂木先生的事情當中
If they start investigating this matter out of interest,
若是他們在興趣的驅使下 開始調查這件事
both Polka and the bespectacled high school girl will be in danger.
波爾卡和那個戴眼鏡的女高中生 都會面臨危險
This is an event that even Mr. Hosorogi
這可是連細呂木先生
had to hide his whereabouts for.
都不得不隱匿自身行蹤的事件
You speak as if you are certain that he is still alive.
你這說法就像是 你很確定他還活著一樣
After all, I have received some intelligence that only I can understand.
畢竟我收到了一些 只有我能明白的情報啊
Forget it.
算了
If you want to play dumb, go ahead.
妳想裝糊塗就繼續裝吧
But listen carefully to me,
但是妳給我聽好了
this time I must cut off the cancerous tumor in the police force
我這次一定要將警察界的毒瘤切掉
and create a place where Mr. Hosorogi can reside.
創造一個 能夠讓細呂木先生回來的地方
Clarissa, what he said just now is…
克拉麗莎 剛才他說的是…
You can ignore it.
妳們無視就好
But Polka might be Mr. Hosorogi's…
可是 波爾卡說不定 是細呂木先生的…
It doesn't matter.
無妨
That person is definitely only thinking about money.
那個人的腦子里肯定只想著錢
He wouldn't care about someone like me.
哪裡顧得上我這種人啊
Hosorogi and Clarissa.
細呂木 以及克拉麗莎…
It seems necessary for me to investigate the people in this bar.
看來我有必要 對這家酒吧的人進行一番調查了
I must crush these poisonous insects
我必須要擊潰
who are close to the Master.
這些接近主公大人的毒蟲
The prosecutor of the Metropolitan Police Department!
警視廳的檢察官
What is a prosecutor?
檢察官是什麼
Prosecutor will supervise internal misconduct of the police.
是對警察內部的瀆職行為 進行督察的職務
Speaking of which,
啊 說起來
IMPERIAL GORGEOUS UNIT, DEPUTY CHIEF OF APPRAISAL AND RESTRAINT AGENCY, JUNGGLAD DILOMLEAGUE XIV there are similar roles in my world too.
(帝國絢爛隊 調查追蹤機關副主任 詹格勒迪隆里格14世) 我那邊的世界裡也有類似的職務
So, Mr. Hosorogi,
這麼說 細呂木先生
are you saying that you're the superior of those detectives?
難道你是那些刑警們的上司嗎
ALTHOUGH WE'RE NOT IN THE SAME DEPARTMENT
(雖然不是同一個部門)
BUT WE KNOW EACH OTHER
(但我們彼此之間是認識的)
Really?
真的假的
Incredible.
難以置信
Did you do anything that fit the role of a prosecutor?
你這傢伙有過 符合檢察官身份的舉動嗎
BACK THEN I WAS OFTEN CALLED A DELINQUENT INSPECTOR AND A SCUMBAG WHO EXPOSED SCUM.
(哼哼哼…想當年我可是經常被稱作 “不良警官”和“揭露污穢的人渣“啊)
So cool.
好帥
What's so cool about?
哪裡帥了
So what did you write on that piece of paper,
所以你到底在那張紙上寫了什麼
Mr. Hosorogi?
細呂木先生
IF YOU WANT TO KNOW, YOU HAVE TO PAY ME INFORMATION FEE.
(想知道的話 你們得付給我情報費)
Were you really a prosecutor before?
你以前真的是檢察官嗎
THE FEE IS 1 MILLION YEN, NOT EVEN ONE LESS Well, I can't afford that much money.
(費用是100萬日元 少一塊都不行) 唔 我拿不出那麼多錢
DON'T WORRY, THERE ARE PLENTY OF WAYS TO MAKE MONEY. LEAVE IT TO ME.
(放心吧 賺錢的方法有得是 包在我身上)
Why are you being so tough?
你在強硬個什麼勁啊
It's just because you wrote something on paper
話說回來 不就是因為你在紙上寫了什麼東西
that the police grabbed Polka's collar?
波爾卡才會被他揪住衣領的嗎
WELL, I REALLY DID SOMETHING WRONG. I APOLOGIZE TO YOU SINCERELY. SORRY.
(嗯 這確實是我做的不對 我向你誠懇地道歉 不好意思)
SORRY FOR INVOLVING YOU GUYS IN THIS MATTER. IT HAS ALWAYS BEEN A HURDLE.
(抱歉把你們捲進來了 這件事一直都是我心裡的一個坎)
Ah, then there's nothing we can do about it.
啊 那就沒辦法了
What does this mean?
這話什麼意思
As for the price of being used by me,
作為任我驅使的代價
I will help him fulfill his unfulfilled wish in this world.
我必須得幫他解決現世未了的心願
This is the contract between Mr. Hosorogi and me.
這便是我和細呂木先生的契約
If his wish has been fulfilled,
我說 要是他心願已了
won't he go to heaven?
不就成佛了嗎
I AM NOT UNGRATEFUL PERSON
(我不是那種忘恩負義的人)
If those police officers can handle things smoothly,
如果那些警察行事順利
will you be able to fulfill a wish?
你就可以了結一項心願
WELL… HOPEFULLY
(嗯…希望如此吧)
Got it.
我知道了
Unfinished wish…
未了的心願…
Then I will have to face Lisa directly.
屆時我將不得不直面麗莎了
The world is both vast and small.
世界既寬廣又狹小
If two people truly wish to meet again from the bottom of their hearts,
若是兩人打從心底希望再次相見
it can be easily achieved.
便可輕而易舉地實現
Don't you think so?
你不這麼認為嗎
Prisoner ID number 243291343432497.
犯人編號24329134 3432497號
You just randomly assigned me a prisoner number.
你這是隨便給我編了一個犯人編號啊
You didn't come to see me just to talk about this, did you?
你應該不是為了 特地說這個才來找我的吧
Tena Sorimura.
雪車村天鵶
No, it should be Phantom Solitaire.
不 怪人雪天鴉
Then I will call you
那麼我就
Your Excellency the Grocer.
稱呼你為雜貨殿閣下吧
But speaking of which, can you act more surprised?
話說回來 你可以表現得再吃驚一點嗎
I hope this joke about the prisoner ID number can make you laugh.
我希望這個犯人編號的玩笑 能夠博君一笑
If you want me to smile, you have to provide something that is worth it.
若是希望我能夠笑出來 那你得提供與之價值相稱的物品
If you can satisfy me even more, I might even refund the difference.
如果你能讓我更加滿意 我甚至還會將差價退還給你
Forget it.
算了
Someday, I will make you laugh.
總有一天我會讓你笑出來的
Today, I just came to make a deal with you.
今天我只是過來找你做交易的
Thank you very much for your preference for my store.
十分感謝您對小店的偏愛
I want to buy intelligence.
我想買的是情報
For everything related to this sign that you know,
你所知道的 和這個標誌相關的事情
I want to buy it all.
我全都想買下來
I certainly have the information you want.
我當然有你想要的情報
So let's talk about the deal.
那麼 我們就來談談交易的事吧
For a starting offer, please provide equivalent information.
作為起始的報價 請你提供與之對等的情報吧
The Grocer.
雜貨殿
According to the information from the Metropolitan Police Department,
警視廳的資料裡是這樣記錄的
it can be traced back to a businessman who existed 100 years ago.
其存在要追溯至 100年前便存在的一位商人
The man arrested by Iwanome
而到了現代
in modern times is a descendant
被岩野目逮捕的這個男人
of that businessman recorded in the data 100 years ago.
是資料裡距今100年前的 那位商人的後代
He was identified as the fifth-generation inheritor of that businessman.
他被認定為那位商人的第五代繼承者
In the disciplined detention center, he created a special space.
他成了以嚴格遵守戒律為宗旨的 拘留所裡一道“特別的風景”
Allowing you to keep this space precisely
而允許你保有此處空間這件事
reflects the essence of the Grocer.
恰恰體現出雜貨殿這一存在的本質
This single-person cell
這間單人牢房
is exactly what he obtained through his dealings with the nation,
正是他和國家進行交易而得來的
and it is also proof of his power.
亦是他力量的證明
He relies neither on force nor knowledge but on trade.
既不靠武力也不靠知識 而是靠交易
This is the simplest power.
這種再簡單不過的力量
From individual lives to national destinies,
從人的性命到國家的命運
there is nothing in this world that cannot be traded.
世界上不存在無法交易的物品
Mass-produced goods, limited editions, stolen items, lost property, sacred relics.
量產商品 限定商品 偷來的贓物 丟失的物品 聖遺物…
Except for one thing, his own heart.
只有一樣事物除外 那便是他自己的內心
I'm not very good at violence,
我不怎麼擅長暴力
but if it comes to a point when I need to deal with issues,
但若是到了不得不動手的時候
I will use playing cards as weapons.
我會將撲克牌當作武器
Why have
為何
people believed that
人們
playing cards could be used as weapons from ancient times to the present?
從古至今都認為 撲克牌可以當作武器來使用呢
I never studied,
本店從不學習
so I don't know about that kind of history.
故而並不知曉那樣的歷史
The answer is only one.
答案只有一個
Because it's cool.
因為帥啊
I see.
原來如此
You have wasted quite a bit of my time.
你浪費了我不少時間
The price needs to be raised a little more.
價格得再提高一點
Wait!
你給我等一下
Didn't you say "For a starting offer, please provide equivalent information"?
你不是說“作為開始談交易的條件 需要給我提供一點情報”嗎
So that's why I told you my valuable information.
所以我才將我珍藏的秘密告訴你的耶
I'm not sure what your standard for "valuable" is.
我不是很清楚你所謂“珍藏”的標準
At least for me,
至少對本店而言
the stock price of Phantom Solitaire has plummeted.
怪人雪天鴉的股價已經暴跌了
SOLITAIRE You are being completely unreasonable.
(雪天鴉) 你太不講理了
This is what I want to say.
這是我要說的話吧
Well, then let me give you another piece of valuable information.
好 那我就再給你 提供一個我珍藏的情報
When counting money,
數錢的時候
applying some oil to your hands
在手上塗點油
can reduce the chance of injuring your fingers.
就可以減少傷到手指的機率
Isn't it enough to wear rubber gloves or apply hand cream?
戴上橡膠手套或是 塗點護手霜不就行了嗎
You, as a rare criminal, yet provide me with such idiotic intelligence.
你身為稀世的罪犯 卻提供給我這樣的智障情報
Okay, it's somewhat valuable.
好吧 也算是有點價值
How could you say something like that to me?
你怎麼這樣
As an exchange of learning,
作為學到東西的交換
I offer you these.
我就為您提供這些吧
DELICIOUS STICKS It should be enough.
(美味棒) 這樣應該足夠了吧
30 yen.
30日元
They taste pretty good, so I'll take them.
味道還是不錯的 我就收下了
But don't try to fool me with food.
不過不要拿食物來糊弄我啊
Quickly present the intelligence that I'm dying to know.
你給我趕快 把我望眼欲穿的情報呈上來
There are many meanings behind the symbols on playing cards.
撲克牌的標誌有很多種意思
As for French playing cards,
法式撲克的話
spades represent swords and clubs represent cudgels.
黑桃代表劍 梅花則是棍棒
Hearts represent cups and diamonds mean money.
紅心代表杯子 方塊則是貨幣的意思
Symbols of all kinds released throughout the world,
遍布在世間的各式各樣的符號
and their simplified results
其簡化後的產物
almost always have some kind of meaning.
幾乎都有著某種含義
For example,
舉例來說
this diagonal line represents a sword.
這條斜線代表劍
There once existed an ancient knightly order in Central and Eastern Europe
曾經存在於中歐至東歐的古老騎士團
that used a crest somewhat similar.
使用過與之略微相似的徽章
However, it is not the same as the one you provided.
不過那和你提供的標誌 可以說是完全不同的東西
Okay, the free trial ends here.
好了 免費試聽的情報就到此為止
If you want to get more information,
若想得到更多情報
you need to provide something of equal value.
你需要提供價值與之對等的物品
Okay, I'm doing this all for the performance.
好吧 我這全是為了公演
You name your price.
你開個價吧
Have you thought about it?
你想好了嗎
My price is based on the amount of money customers have on hand.
本店會根據顧客的所持金額來定價
But when I say "amount of money on hand,"
但我說的所持金額
I don't mean the cash in the wallet.
指的並不是錢包裡有多少錢
Today is the day
今天
mentioned in the Phantom Solitaire preview.
是怪人雪天鴉預告裡說的日子
What kind of action will he take?
他會採取什麼樣的行動呢
Oh? Today?
啊 今天嗎
What is he going to do? I'm so looking forward to it.
不知道他要做什麼 好期待啊
He doesn't seem like the kind of person who would plan a bomb terrorist attack.
他看起來不像是 會策劃炸彈恐怖襲擊的那種人
Good morning.
早上好
What a great morning.
好棒的清晨呢
It's already noon.
已經中午了
Don't worry.
放心吧
You don't need to distinguish between morning and noon when guarding your room.
擔任自己房間的警衛 不需要區分早上和中午
What kind of twisted logic is this?
這是什麼歪理
Morning.
早上好
Hey, what's that?
喂 那是什麼
Wow! Amazing!
哇 好厲害
There's something over Shinjuku there.
現在新宿那邊好像有了什麼動靜
Countless airships appeared in the sky.
天空中出現了無數艘飛艇
Why?
為什麼
I have already been reincarnated into another world, haven't I?
我不是轉生到其他世界了嗎
Polka, do you recognize that sign?
波爾卡 你認識那個標誌嗎
It's unmistakable.
不會錯的
That is
那是
the emblem of the empire that I once lived in.
我曾經待過的世界裡
The empire has long since been destroyed.
已經覆滅的帝國的國徽
(Episode 10: The Emblem)
(#10 The Emblem -國徽-)